Naruto...
Just disappear already...
《サスケ : ナルト 今度こそ消え去れ！
and take our bond along with you!
俺との つながりとともに！》
Sasuke wins!
((イルカ : サスケの勝利。
All right, you two...
make the Unison Sign.
では互いに和解の印を。
You wanna piece of me, you loser?
(フン！
やんのか？ 落ちこぼれが))
What is this?
これは？
Sasuke...
If you and I fight...
((サスケ お前と俺が戦えば→
We'll both...
(２人とも 死ぬ))
die.
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
Am I dead?
This sensation...
死んだ？
It must be...
この感覚ってば…。
Probably.
そういうことなんだろうな。
たぶん。
Pitiful, isn't it?
惨めだな。
うん？
You had the Nine Tails...
and I was an Uchiha.
お前は 九尾。
We were ostracized from the village
and treated like outcasts.
俺は うちはの名によって
里から疎まれ→
And we resented the village
and its people.
除け者にされていた。
そして俺たちは里を…。
Right?
里の連中を怨んだ …だろ？
I won't let you say I'm wrong.
((違うとは言わせねえ))
You called me your brother...
In that sense, perhaps we were.
お前は俺を兄弟と呼んだが→
You're totally wrong!
そういう意味じゃ
確かにそうかもな。
Damn it,
you don't understand, do you?
全然違えよ。
…と オメエ
わかってねえんだな！
Sorry, Grandma Tsunade...
悪い 綱手のばあちゃん。
I promised... I wouldn't die...
絶対死なねえって
約束してたのに。
until I became the Hokage...
火影になるまで。
Oh yeah! The Infinite Tsukuyomi!
This is bad!
あっ そうだ！ 無限月読。
The Release Jutsu can't be activated
without us being there, right?!
やべえじゃん 俺らがいなきゃ
解術できねえんじゃねえか。
You're dead... and you're worried
about what happens to the world?
死んでも まだ世界の行く末が
気になるっていうのか？
Of course!
We can't leave it like that!
あたりめえだろ あのままで
いいわけねえだろうが。
Sakura and Kakashi still remain.
They'll figure something out.
サクラとカカシがまだ残ってる。
なんとかするだろ。
I hope so.
だといいけど…。
Naruto!
うっ…。
ナルト？
The Hokage, huh...
火影か…。
Pretty soon, Big Brother, they might
carve your Great Stone Face over there!
((兄さんも もうすぐしたら→
あそこに顔岩
作ってもらえるかもね。
Big Brother?
兄さん？
Forgive me, Sasuke.
This is it.
(イタチ)許せ サスケ。
これで最後だ。
And no matter what you do
from here on out, know this...
お前が これからどうなろうと→
I will love you always.
(俺は お前をずっと愛している))
Big Brother...
《兄さん もうすぐ会える》
I'll be seeing you... soon.
You've finally come to, eh?
やっと戻ってきたかよ。
うっ…。
As you can see...
if either of us moves too much,
we'll bleed out and die.
見てのとおりだ。
お前も俺も あまり動くと
血出すぎで死ぬぞ。
Why would you go that far?
Why do all that...
just to get in my way?
そんなになってまで
なぜ 俺の邪魔をしたがる？
I gained the power to enter the darkness,
and sever all bonds...
俺は闇に入り→
And naturally, everyone's tried to cut
their ties to me as well, at some point.
すべてを切るための力を得た。
どんなやつでも当然→
そんな俺とのつながりを
一度は皆 切ろうとした。
But you...
You've never attempted
to cut me off.
だが お前は→
The only one who can handle
all that hatred is me!
俺を決して切ろうとはしなかった。
((お前の憎しみを
受けてやれんのは→
Why do you keep
involving yourself with me?
(俺しかいねえ！))
なぜ そこまでして
俺にかかわろうとする？
You already know, don't you?
Now that your body can't move,
your mouth sure is moving a lot.
もう わかってんだろ？
Just answer me!
体が動かねえからって
やけに口がよく動くじゃ…。
いいから答えろ！
'Cuz you're my friend.
What is it with you anyway?
友達だからだ。
I'm your friend!
((お前は いったい何なんだ？
Just what the hell do you want?
Why are you so fixated on me?
友達だ。
テメエは いったい
何がしてえんだよ？
It's because I'm your friend!
なんで俺に そこまでこだわる？
(友達だからだ))
I've heard that before.
But what exactly does that mean
to you anyway?
それは かつて聞いた。
お前にとっての それは→
You ask me to explain it,
but I really can't put it into words.
いったい何なんだ？
それを説明しろって言われても→
It's just that...
正直 俺も よくわからねえよ。
when I see you take on stuff...
ただ… お前のそういう→
and get all messed up...
It kinda...
背負って
ゴチャゴチャしてるとこ見てっと→
hurts me.
なんでか… 俺が 痛えんだ。
It hurts so much inside,
that I can't just leave it alone, y'know?
すっげえ痛くて→
とてもじゃねえけど→
Though right now, I'm in a lot of pain
all over, and I can't do anything about it.
そのまま
ほっとけねえんだってばよ。
今はさすがに あちこち痛くて
どうにもならねえけどな。
イテテ…。
Naruto... I knew you were
always alone back then.
《ナルト お前が昔
常に一人でいるのは知っていた。
The village shunned you,
just like they did with me...
the lone Uchiha survivor.
生き残った うちはの俺と同じで→
You intentionally did stupid things
to get scolded,
里で皆に阻害されていたな。
most likely to get people's attention.
バカなことをしては
わざと叱られようとしていた。
In the beginning, I thought
you were good for nothing.
他人と関わるためだろう。
A weakling who just constantly
wanted to goof around.
最初は そんなお前を見て
くだらないやつだと思った。
But the more I watched you being idiotic
and getting scolded over and over...
じゃれたいだけの弱いやつだと。
For some reason,
it started weighing on my mind.
だが 何度も叱られているお前を
ずっと見ていると→
I thought back then, that your weakness
was gradually rubbing off on me.
なぜだか気になるようになった。
そのとき思った。
Then, every time I'd see you,
I'd think about you more and more.
お前の弱さが だんだん
俺に染まってきたんだと。
それからのお前を見るたびに→
Seeing you desperately
trying to bond with others...
どんどん
気になるようになっていった。
made me remember my own family.
他人とつながろうと
必死なお前を見ていると→
And I don't know why,
but I felt relief.
俺の家族を思い出すようになった。
そして なぜだか 安心したんだ。
But at the same time,
I considered it a weakness.
だが それは
同時に弱さだと思った。
I trained hard
as if to escape that weakness.
In order to get my revenge
on my brother
俺は その弱さから
逃げるように修業した。
to become stronger than him.
兄への復讐のために
兄より強くなるために。
And yet... I ended up
on the same team as you.
And I began thinking about
my family again.
なのに
お前と同じ班になっちまった。
I went on missions with you
そして また家族がチラつく。
as you jabbered on and on
about becoming Hokage...
I saw how both of us
were getting stronger...
火影になりたいとほざく
お前と一緒に任務をこなし→
And one day, I started to feel
the desire to fight you too.
互いに強くなっていくのを
実感した俺は→
いつしか お前とも闘いたい
そう思うようにもなった。
And I began to see a shadow
of my own family in Squad 7...
そして俺は 七班に
己の家族の影を見るようになった。
That's why every time
I saw you suffering...
だから
お前の苦しむ姿を見るたび→
That's right...
I felt it...
I felt pain too.
そう 俺も…。
When I understood your hurt,
I finally saw you as a comrade.
俺が痛くなったんだ。
お前の痛みがわかったとき
初めて仲間と思えた。
But on the other hand...
I couldn't leave you alone.
You were getting stronger and stronger.
そして その反面→
Watching you steadily get stronger...
急速に強くなっていくお前を
ほっておけなくなった。
I...
どんどん強くなっていく
お前を見て→
I knew that you were always alone.
俺は…》
I wanted to walk over and start talking.
((俺だって いつもお前が
一人なのは知ってた。
I'd get sort of giddy.
すぐにでも話しかけたかった。
But I stopped myself.
なんか 嬉しくってよ。
I was jealous because
you were good at everything.
けど そりゃやめた。
So I made you my rival.
なんでもできるお前が
うらやましくって。
You've been...
俺は勝手に
お前を俺のライバルに決めた。
my goal.
お前は俺の… 目標になった。
I had nothing, and I found a bond.
I wanted to be strong
and cool like you.
何にもなかった俺が
つながりを持てた。
That's why I kept chasing after you.
お前みたく
強く かっこよくなりたくて→
It was the opposite.
(ずっと お前の後を追いかけてた))
In reality, I was the one
who was jealous of you.
《逆だ。
Because you had a strength
that I didn't.
本当は俺が
うらやましかったんだ。
You were always walking
in front of me.
俺にはない強さがあったから。
お前はいつも
俺の前を歩いてやがった。
Just like my late Big Brother.
まるで かつての兄さんのように。
And... even today...
そして 今日も…》
I'll let you deal with Sasuke.
That was my plan from the start!
((サスケはお前に任せる))
Entrusting it to you was
the right thing to do, after all.
((端っから そのつもりだ。
These are—!
(やはり お前に託して
正解だった))
Naruto's memories.
My dream...
《これは… ナルトの記憶》
is to surpass the Hokage one day!
And that's why I'm going to
((将来の夢は… 火影を超す！
make everyone in the village
acknowledge me!
んでもって 里のやつら全員に
俺の存在を認めさせてやるんだ！
I have to be ready...
I'm gonna be called the Hokage,
someone that everyone acknowledges.
やっぱ覚悟しとかなきゃな。
みんながみんな認めてくれる
火影ってすげえ名前語るのによ→
There's no such thing as a shortcut!
Quit messin' around,
I'll never run away!
ぜってえ
近道なんかねえってことはよ。
I will make it!
なめんじゃねえ 俺は逃げねえぞ！
Even if I stay a genin
for the rest of my life,
I'll become the Hokage.
So I don't care!
受けてやる！
もし一生 下忍になったって→
意地でも火影になってやるから
べつにいいってばよ！
I never go back on my word.
That's my Ninja Way!
まっすぐ自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
I'm different from you.
俺の忍道だ！
I'm absolutely gonna
become the Hokage.
俺ってば お前と違って
絶対 火影の名前を受け継ぐんだ。
Becoming the Hokage
is my dream.
I won't die...
until I become the Hokage!
火影は 俺の夢だから！
俺は火影になるまで
ぜってえ 死なねえからよ！
I'm gonna become the Hokage
to surpass all the previous ones!
That's my dream, you idiot!
俺は どの先代をも超える
火影になる！
The Hokage is someone
who endures the pain
それが俺の夢だ バカ野郎！
and takes the lead
in front of everyone.
火影ってのは 痛えのを我慢して→
So a Hokage never walks over
his comrades' corpses.
みんなの前を歩いている
やつのことだ。
There is no shortcut
to becoming the Hokage!
だから仲間の死体を
またぐようなことは→
決してねえ！
And there are no ways out
for the one who becomes Hokage!
火影になるやつに近道はねえし→
なったやつに逃げ道はねえんだよ。
No way can a guy who can't even
save one friend become the Hokage.
仲間一人救えねえやつが
火影になんてなれるかよ。
Isn't that right, Sasuke?
(そうだろ サスケ))
Naruto...
How far... have you—?
《ナルト…。
お前は これほどまでに…》
No matter how powerful
you become,
don't try to shoulder
everything alone.
((イタチ : どんなに強くなろうとも→
You share your father's dream,
don't you?
すべてを背負おうとするな。
Then don't ever forget...
お前の夢は確か父と同じだったな。
Becoming Hokage doesn't mean
people will acknowledge you.
なら 覚えておけ。
But when the people acknowledge you,
you can become Hokage.
火影になった者が
皆に認められるんじゃない。
皆から認められた者が
火影になるんだ。
Never forget your friends!
(仲間を忘れるな))
Big Brother...
《兄さん…》
I see.
Then...
そうか…。
show me...
それなら 見せてくれ。
Where are we?
Don't tell me this is really
Heaven this time?
どこだ？ ここ…。
Looks like we fell asleep
and slept until morning.
まさか 今度こそ
マジで天国なんじゃ…。
どうやら 俺たちは
朝まで寝ちまったようだな。
We've failed to die again.
また 死に損なったようだ。
Damn it! I still can't move!
うぅ…。
I was hoping to punch you hard and
make you finally open your eyes!
クソ… まだ 体が動かねえや。
お前 ぶん殴って 今こそ 本当に→
目 覚まさせてやろうと
思ったのに。
W-What is it?
フフフ… ハハハハハ！
We're messed up like this,
and you still wanna fight?
な… なんだよ？
Damn right! No matter
how many times it takes—
こんなになって
まだ やる気かよ？
I admit it.
当たりめえだ！ 何度だって…。
I've...
認めてやるよ。
lost.
俺の…。
負けだ。
You idiot!
This fight isn't about winning or losing!
バカ野郎！
It's about punching a sulking friend,
to make him snap out of it!
この戦いは 勝ちとか負けとか
そんなんじゃねえ！
That's what it's about!
The real match that I want,
comes after that!
ダチが すねてっから
１発 ぶん殴って→
目 覚ましてやろうって話だ。
Hey, Naruto...
俺のやりてぇ勝負は
そのあとだってばよ！
I just acknowledged you.
なぁ ナルト。
あぁ!?
俺は お前を認めちまった。
If I die here, the long cycle of destiny
the Sage of Six Paths mentioned
will probably end as well.
ここで 俺が死ねば→
This is... a kind of revolution too.
六道仙人の言う
長き因縁も終わるだろう。
You can release the Infinite Tsukuyomi
after I'm dead,
これも ひとつの革命だ。
by transplanting my left eye
into Kakashi or someone else.
無限月読の解術は→
俺の死後 左目を
カカシにでも移植してやればいい。
I'll put an end to myself.
俺は 俺自身で
己に決着をつける。
By dying?
Don't think dying will settle this!
死んで…
死んで 決着つくなんて思うなよ。
If you're willing to die,
then live and help me instead.
What I want to do is to make
all shinobi cooperate with each other.
死ぬくらいなら
生きて 俺に協力しろ。
And that definitely includes you!
俺のやりたいことは
全忍の協力だ。
Just because you want that
doesn't mean others will agree to it.
もちろん お前も含めてだぞ。
Damn it! If you keep whining and sulking,
I'll slug you again!
お前が それでよくても
他の者は納得しない。
ったく… それ以上 すねて
グチグチ言ってみろ。
There's no guarantee
I won't stand against you again...
また ぶっとばすぞ！
Then I'll stop you again!
俺が また
お前に たてつくかも わからんぞ。
Besides, I know you're not going to
do that kinda thing anymore.
そしたら また 止める！
How can you be so sure?
つうか もう お前は
そんなこと しねえよ。
Don't make me repeat myself!
なぜ そう言いきれる？
これ以上 同じことを言わせんな。
Haven't you figured it out yet?!
Now that I think about it...
お前のほうは
まだ わかってねえのかよ…。
You were always pretty stupid too...
そういや お前も
意外に バカだったもんな。
boku ni wa wakaru nda uso o tsuite iru kimi ga
I can tell when you're lying
naite ii yo koko ni zutto irukara
It's okay to cry because I'll always be here
sekaijuu ni koborete iru hontou no ai no kimochi
Feelings of true love spills out throughout the world
sagashidashite miushinatte yoake ga kuru no matteru
We search for it but lose it, while waiting for daybreak
migi no hoshi ni wa boku no namae o tsukete
The star on the right will bear my name
kimi ga yonde okureyo
Will you call out to it?
hidari no hoshi ni wa kimi no namae ga ne
The star on the left will bear your name
niau yo zutto soba ni irukara
It's perfect, because we'll always be together
"THE UNISON SIGN"
Shut up, you loser.
うるせぇよ… ウスラトンカチ。
ハハハッ！
I'll start knowing your pain
and feelings too.
You never cut me off.
You kept trying to get closer
to my feelings.
You never stopping
calling me your friend.
Even though I tried to sever
those feelings myself.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Naruto Uzumaki!"
You stopped me, as a friend.